Ayse Hunt

(206) 696 - 3601 | aysehunt@gmail.com | aysehunt.com

Summary

I am a software developer with a background in mixed-methods research and human-computer interaction. I'm passionate about creating digital experiences that are intuitive and that resonate with end users. Through my Bachelor's and Master's degrees, I focused on developing educational technology. In the past, I have worked with museums to research, design, and evaluate interactive technology in exhibits.

Education

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY

Masters in Learning Sciences, Sept. 2020 – January 2023

UNIVERSITY OF PUGET SOUND

B.S. in Computer Science and B.A. in Art History, Aug. 2015 – May 2019

Experience

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY

Osmo Coding Research Assistant, Jan. 2021 - present

- · Conducted a mixed-methods analysis of children's collaboration while playing a computational game
- · Systematically compared how two different interfaces influenced children's behavior
- · Ran statistical analysis in Excel and Stata and synthesized quantitative findings for publication

Street Code Jam Fest Research Assistant, Sept. 2020 – June 2021

- · Assisted in hiring and training 15 undergraduate students to teach computer science program
- · Created and managed a Qualtrics consent form for parents of after-school students

ADLER PLANETARIUM

Visiting Researcher, Sept. 2021 – June 2022

- · Identified usability and accessibility issues of an interactive touch table in an existing museum exhibit
- · Iterated on existing UI in order to align with reading comprehension of children aged 6-13
- · Held feedback sessions with 25 middle school youth to refine exhibit prototypes

VULCAN, INC.

Arts & Entertainment Assistant, Sept. - Dec. 2019

- · Designed a Smartsheet dashboard to improve internal communication between 6 departments
- · Facilitated the transition to the new calendar system utilizing principles of change management

Living Computers: Museum + Labs Curatorial Intern, June - Aug. 2019

- · Designed a mixed-methods study to evaluate visitor experiences in an existing museum exhibit
- · Achieved buy-in from key stakeholders to move forward with my proposed design recommendations

MUSEUM OF GLASS

Student lead and Android developer, Nov. 2018 – June 2019

- · Led a team of other 3 students in developing an Android application featuring museum artifacts
- · Designed the front-end of the application based on data from my 2018 ethnographic study
- · Collaborated with curators and exhibit designers to design a physical kiosk to house the application

UNIVERSITY OF PUGET SOUND

Humanities Undergraduate Researcher, June 2018 - May 2019

- · Conducted an ethnographic study on the use of educational technology in art museums
- · Paper accepted and presented at the 2018 Art Museum in the Digital Age conference in Vienna, Austria STEM Undergraduate Researcher, June 2017 Dec. 2018
- Built a Java program to study the habits of people learning to program
- · Paper accepted and presented at the 2018 Koli Calling International Conference on Computer Science Education

Experience continued

MARRIOT RESIDENCE INN, SOUTH LAKE UNION SEATTLE

Front Desk Associate, June 2016 - Aug. 2016

- · Direct customer service experience within the front desk and concierge team
- · Assisted 70+ guests daily with check-ins, check-outs, cashiering, and concierge needs
- · Facilitated communication between housekeeping, operations, and front desk team

Skills

Languages Java, Python, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, SQL, Haskell, Prolog **Methods** Survey studies, interview studies, interaction analysis, co-design sessions, quantitative analysis **Applications** Qualtrics, Smartsheet, Tableau, G Suite, Microsoft Office, SharePoint, SurveyMonkey **Conference Presentations** Please see tinyurl.com/aysehunt